Cheng-Yu (Alan) Chuang

San Francisco, CA • chengyualantw@gmail.com • 415-405-6593 • www.linkedin.com/in/cy-alan-chuang

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with a master's degree in Computer Science and 5 years of industry experience transforming business requirements and functional specifications into software solutions and improving efficiency, scalability, and stability of various system resources. Experienced with Microservice, incorporating Spring Boot, Eureka, and Kafka. Demonstrates proficiency in Java, with strong system design skills on the backend. Adept at keeping pace with evolving Machine Learning technology.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant | SAN FRANCISCO STATE UNIVERSITY

2021-12 - PRESENT

- Created a website utilizing deep learning techniques to assist blind and visually impaired communities in accessing videos
 Java, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Python, PyTorch, MySQL, REST API, JSON, Docker, Linux
- Accomplished research work by improving video description AI model to be state-of-the-art model, resulting in an average 2.58% increase in all scores

Senior Software Engineer | TRADEBEYOND (FORMERLY CBX SOFTWARE)

2019-09 - 2020-11

- Developed supply chain systems with over 30,000 retail & supplier partners, and 50,000 users in more than 50 countries –
 Java, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, MongoDB, Elasticsearch, REST API, JSON, Gitlab, Jenkins, Docker, Linux, Azure, AWS
 S3, HTTP, Eureka, Kafka, Microservice
- Promoted to Senior Software Engineer based on extraordinary performance and team collaboration
- Implemented Netflix Eureka as service discovery and Kafka as message broker to decouple back-end services
- Integrated Sonar Qube into development workflow, eliminating over 100 potential bugs and elevating code quality through automated code reviews that efficiently identify and rectify bugs
- Conducted a cross-team presentation on utilizing HotSwap within IntelliJ to optimize the development and debugging
 processes, resulting in improved efficiency and productivity
- Introduced JUnit and Mockito into development process to enhance code quality through unit testing and test-driven development practices
- Implemented JMeter integration within CI/CD pipeline, enabling automated stress testing as an integral part of deployment process
- Managed development timeline using Jira and Agile methodologies, ensuring efficient project planning and execution

Software Engineer | HUNG YANG SOFTWARE

2017-08 - 2019-07

- Maintained an ERP system for Far EasTone, third-largest telecommunications company in Taiwan Java, JavaScript,
 JSP, Oracle SQL, Tomcat, Linux, SVN
- Minimized 30% development and maintenance effort by developing a new system architecture
- Reduced average CPU and RAM usage by 15% through data migration to a new system
- Decreased average 65% loading time of JSP module of pages by adjusting algorithm
- Rated top performer in the department twice among 120 Software Engineers (2018 & 2019)

Software Engineer | LEADTEK RESEARCH

2015-09 - 2017-06

- Developed 2 Android healthcare applications assisting users in tracking and recording health data Java, Android, SQLite
- Created a kiosk system for over 20 hospitals to help patients record health data Java, Android, SQLite, SOAP

EDUCATION

M.S. in Computer Science | SAN FRANCISCO STATE UNIVERSITY | 4.0 GPA

2021-2023

B.E. in Computer Science and Information Engineering | NATIONAL CENTRAL UNIVERSITY

2010-2014

SKILL

Languages: Java, Python, C/C++, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, JSON

Database: SQL (Oracle SQL, MySQL, SQLite), NoSQL (MongoDB, Elasticsearch)

Frameworks: Node.js, React, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Express.js, Android, iOS, JUnit, Mockito, REST API **Developer Tools**: Microsoft Azure, AWS S3, Git, SVN, Docker, JMeter, Jenkins, IntelliJ, Eclipse, VS Code, Kafka, Eureka